Register of the Claude Emerson Welch Collection, 1951-1965
Hoover Institution Archives
Claude Emerson Welch Collection,
1951-1965
73006
Welch, Claude Emerson
1 manuscript box 0.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Pamphlets, government issuances, transcripts of interviews, and ephemeral publications, relating to the political development of West Africa. Used as research material for C. E. Welch's book, Dream of Unity, Pan-Africanism and Political Unification in West Africa (1966).
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1973.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Pan-Africanism.; Africa.; Africa, West.; Africa, West--Politics and government.
Container List
- Cameroon (Box 1.)
  - Documents of Cameroonian history prepared by David E. Gardinier
  - Directeur du Parti de l'Union Camerounaise, Lettre Ouverte à Monsieur le Président Général et à Messieurs les Membres du Comité
  - Union des Populations du Cameroon, "Unification immédiate du Cameroon," 1952(?), 43p.
  - World Federation of Democratic Youth, "La F.M.J.D. réaffirme son soutien à la jeunesse combattante du Kamerun," Le Caire, 1960, 12p.
  - Cameroon - "Constitution." Project soumis au referendum populaire, 4p.
  - Le Crabe Noir (Yaounde, Cameroon), Première Année, No.1, 28 août 1960
  - L'Aube (Yaounde, Cameroon), No.1, 24 février 1961
  - Union des Populations du Cameroon. Bureau National Provisoire, "Dernier mot de l'UPC sur le problème de la réunification du Cameroun," Yaounde, 2 février 1961
  - L'Echo du Cameroun (Douala) lère Année, No. 24, 31 mai 1954
  - L'Etincelle (Yaounde, Cameroun), Première Année, No.1, 1-10 mars 1961
  - Étoile (Yaounde, Cameroun), 6ème Année, No.1, n.d.
  - Nyobé, Ruben Um. "La pensée de Um Nyobé,", 78p.
  - Kamerun National Democratic Party, "The Manifesto of the KNDP, 1961,", 6p.
  - Mabaya, Jean Baptiste, "Discours prononcé par... Président de l'Assemblée Législative du Cameroun à l'ouverture de la première session ordinaire annuelle de l'année legislative, 1959-1960," 19 octobre 1959., 16p.
  - Mbida, André-Marie, "Discours d'investiture prononcé par... Premier Ministre...15 mai 1957 devant l'Assemblee Législative du Cameroun,", 33p.
  - Mbida, André-Marie, "Discours prononcé à Edea par...Premier Ministre...26 juin 1957,", 10p.
  - Achu, P. A., "Western Cameroonians, a Post Plebiscite Survey," Lagos, 1962, 20p.
  - Cameroun. Assemblée Territoriale - Session Budgétaire de mars-avril 1957, "Analyse des enseignements tirés du bilan d'ensemble des premiers plans quadriennaux et solutions proposes," par le Président de la Commission...A. Mandon, 40p.
  - Nigeria. Ministry of Research and Information, "Financial Assistance to the Cameroon,", 7p.
- Central African Republic
  - "A Monsieur le Président-Fondateur du Mouvement de l'Evolution Sociale de l'Afrique Noire (M.E.S.A.N.)," Bangui, avril 1957, 4p.
  - "L'éducation et l'émancipation du peuple oubanguien par le regroupment de l'élite: Emancipation Oubanguienne" 1958(?)
  - "Réponses à la conférence donnée par les M.E.S.A.N.S. et l'Union des Capitalistes de Bangui, le 12 novembre 1956,", 3p.
  - Terre Africaine. Organe du Mouvement d'Evolution Sociale de l'Afrique Noire, Bangui, Oubangui-Chari. No.5, décembre 1958
  - Boganda, Barthélémy, "Lettre aux militants," Bangui, Mouvement de l'Evolution Sociale de l'Afrique Noire, 15 septembre 1956
- Chad - Liste des Députés du Tchad par Préfecture (elected 1959), 2p.
- Committee of African Organizations, United Africa (official organ), London 1963 March-April
- Congo
  - A.E.F. Nouvelle. Rassemblement Démocratique Africain pour l'A.E.F., Brazzaville, lère année, No.2, septembre 1948
  - Notes, 4p.
  - Ministère de l'Intérieur. Direction de l'Administration Générale, "Instruction pour l'élection des Députés à l'Assemblée Législative," Pointe-Noire, 14 mai 1959
  - Ministère de l'Information. Notice biographique, Abbé Fulbert Youlou, Président..., 2p.
  - Bulletin Intérieur, No.6, Après le referendum, 2p.
  - Afrique Equatoriale Française. Haut-Commissariat, "Objet: Elections," Brazzaville, 21 mai 1951, 15p.
  - Révision des listes électorales et modalités du scrutin pour les élections municipales, Brazzaville
  - Ministère de l'Information. Notice biographique, M. Faustin Okomba, Ministre du Travail, 1p.
  - Ministère de l'Information. Notice biographique, M. Isaac Ibouanga...and others
- French Africa
  - Congrès des Indépendants d'Outre-Mer de Bobo-Dioulasso, 12, 13, 14, 15 février 1953. Résolutions et statuts, 20p.
  - Dia, Mamadou, letter, Paris, 25 mars 1953, 1p.
  - Journées d'Etudes des Indépendants d'Outre-Mer, 40p.
  - Décret No. 58-744 du 20 août 1958 portant convocation des collèges électoraux des Territoires d'Outre-Mer
  - Décret No. 58-748 du 20 août 1958 portant convocation des collèges électoraux des Territoires d'Outre-Mer
  - Ministère de l'Intérieur. Ordonnance No. 58-734 du 20 août 1958 portant organization du referendum, Paris, 20 août 1958, 3p.
  - Ministère de la France d'Outre-Mer. Direction des Affaires Politiques 2 Bureau, "Le syndicalisme dans les territories africains,", 35p.
  - Décret No. 58-749 du 20 août 1958 règlant les conditions d'application dans les territories d'Outre-Mer de l'ordonnance No. 58-734 du 20 août 1958 portant organization du referendum prévu par la loi constitutionelle du 3 juin 1958
  - Ministère de la France d'Outre-Mer. Circulaire No. 10.175, "Object: Elections générales à l'Assemblée Nationale du 2 janvier 1956. Organisation et fonctionnement des bureaux de vote. Opérations électorales," Paris, 10 décembre 1955, 8p.
  - Décret No. 58-745 du 20 août 1958 fixant, pour les Territoires d'Outre-Mer, le modèle et le libellé des bulletins de vote à employer pour le referendum prévu par la loi constitutionnelle du 3 juin 1958, 2p.
- French West Africa - Base Mystico-Politique des Institutions en A.O.F.
- Ghana - Ghana Students Association
- Mali - Interview with Amadou Au, Mali Federal Minister of Public Works and Transport, 1959 September 28, 4p.
- Sénégal
  - Haut Commissariat...en Afrique Occidentale Française. Direction Générale de l'Interieur. Service des Affaires Politiques. Note de renseignements, cadres de l'Islam au Sénégal, mise à jour en juin 1952, 15p.
  - Parti Communiste Sénégalais, "Manifeste," Dakar, ler mai 1965, 6p.
  - Bureau National du F.N.S. Typescript, 1p.
  - P.F.A. Comité Directeur. Resolutions. Déclaration du Président Senghor, Dakar, 23 et 24 septembre 1959, 20p.
  - "Bilan et Perspectives." Exposé de M. Mamadou Dia, Vice-Président du Conseil de Gouvernement du Sénégal devant l'Assemblée Territoriale le 20 décembre 1957, 12p.
- Sudan - Union Soundanaise. Congrès Extraordinaire, ler Bamako, 22 septembre 1960. Résolution politique, 2p.
- Togo
  - Organigramme institutionnel de l'union nationale
  - Mise au point de la Juvento "Mouvement Nationaliste Togolais" adressée le 14 août 1961 à Monsieur le Ministre de l'Intérieur de l'Information et de la Presse du Gouvernement de la République Togolaise